Bloomington Gay and Lesbian Alliance newsletters, 1979-1981 C737
Indiana University Archives
Bloomington Gay and Lesbian Alliance newsletters
1979-1981
Indiana University Archives
Bloomington (Ind.) Gay Alliance (1971-1981)
Bloomington (Ind.) Gay and Lesbian Alliance (1981-unknown)
C737
0.1 cubic feet 1 folder
The Bloomington Gay Alliance was an umbrella organization that coordinated many smaller activist and social groups of the Bloomington LGBTQ+ community during the 1970s and 80s. This collection consists of ten newsletters the group published.
Arrangement
Items are arranged chronologically
Biographical / Historical
Initially known as The Bloomington Gay Liberation Front in 1970, the BGLF formed alongside many other similar organizations across the nation in the wake of the Stonewall uprising in 1969 and was at first intended as a radical political organization and protest group. The group quickly became more of a social organization and changed its name to the Bloomington Gay Alliance in 1971. With this name change, many women left the organization to organize separately. Over the next several years, talks continued with the desire to make the organization more representative of women as well as men. To this end, the group underwent structural changes such as adding a co-chair position so that it would be headed by one man and one woman at all times, and in 1981, changed its name again, to become The Bloomington Gay and Lesbian Alliance. This organization sponsored many protests and an annual "Gay Awareness" conference, established a telephone "rap line," called regular meetings, and coordinated a wide variety of subgroups including a speaker's bureau, legal groups, and advice and support groups among others. The group was active until at least 1981.
Related Materials
Additional copies of some of these items and related material are available at the Kinsey Institute.
Related photographs may be available in the University Archives Photographs Database.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of newsletters under two names: Gay News (October 1979-September 1980) and Lesbian and Gay News (April 1981-September/October 1981). Both functioned as the official publication of the Bloomington Gay Alliance/Bloomington Gay and Lesbian Alliance. Issues included news of the organizations, such as their history, structural changes, and elections. Stories also consisted of organizing information to make readers aware of the various social and activist subgroups throughout the town, as well as local businesses that were open to LGBTQ clientele, and general news about the state of politics at the local regional and national levels.
- Bloomington Gay Alliance newsletters and flyers, 1979-1981
  - Gay News
    - October 1979 (Box SC 22)
    - November 1979 (Box SC 22)
    - December 1979 (Box SC 22)
    - March 1980, 2 Copies 2 copies (Box SC 22)
    - September 1980 (Box SC 22)
  - Lesbian and Gay News
    - April 1981 (Box SC 22)
    - May 1981 (Box SC 22)
    - June 1981 (Box SC 22)
    - July-August 1981 (Box SC 22)
    - September-October 1981 (Box SC 22)